Edgar F. Schilder Papers
Edgar F. Schilder Papers
1909-1950
Schilder, Edgar F.
14.5 linear ft.
Over 1,000 pieces of original cartoon artwork including material from the Syracuse Post-Standard, comic strips, original artwork by other cartoonists, biographical material, photographs, newspaper and magazine clippings, proofs, posters, and a scrapbook.
149568
Biographical History
Edgar F. "Steve" Schilder (1888-1963) was an American cartoonist who worked for the Syracuse Post-Standard for over 40 years.
Edgar Francis "Steve" Schilder was born in Chillicothe, Ohio on August 31, 1888. A self-taught artist, Schilder completed courses through the Evans Correspondence School of Cartooning in Columbus, Ohio and his early cartoons were done on chalk plates. His first journalism job was with the Chillicothe newspaper, where he worked for several months without pay in order to gain experience. Schilder then held a string of newspaper positions around the United States.
Schilder worked at the Columbus Citizen, the Portsmouth Blade and in Lima, Ohio. Schilder then went to the Denver Post, the St. Joseph Missouri News Press and the Indianapolis Star. During his tenure in Indianapolis, Schilder picked up his pen name "Steve" which was derived from the black cat that appeared in many of his cartoons. Leaving Indianapolis, Schilder spent a year and a half with the Journal Gazette in Fort Wayne, Indiana before taking a job in Baltimore with the International Syndicate.
In 1914 Schilder worked in St. Louis, in 1915 in Atlanta, and in 1916 he worked at the New Orleans Times Picayune until in 1917, Schilder took a job with the Syracuse Post-Standard and became editor of the newspaper's Sunday magazine. As editor, Schilder's decision to publish historic photos in the magazine proved popular with readers and he ran the newspaper’s photography contests. Schilder also worked as the editorial cartoonist. The New York Herald Tribune, New York Times and the Saturday Evening Post also published Schilder's cartoons.
The United States Treasury Department recognized him with an award in 1940 for his war bond cartoons, and his cartoons of prominent World War II figures were exhibited at the Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts in 1943. The demands of the Post-Standard's Sunday magazine led Schilder to spend less time on cartooning during his final years with the newspaper. Schilder retired from the Post-Standard on July 1, 1962.
Edgar F. Schilder died on August 25, 1963 after falling in his home and suffering a skull fracture.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Edgar F. Schilder Papers are divided into six series: original artwork, biographical material, printed material, clippings, proofs and photographs.
Original Artwork (1918-1950) contains original pieces drawn by Schilder and other cartoonists. Schilder's items include primarily both editorial and general interest cartoons.
Schilder’s work reflects the interests of his Syracuse and Central New York readership. His numerous cartoons related to fishing often referenced Oneida Lake. Winter is a prominent topic as well as a backdrop for his cartoons while those depicted go about their daily lives, such as Schilder's recurring character, Might Marty, a balding, bespeckled man who is no more than a head on a stick figure body. Local college sports teams and the Syracuse Chiefs minor league baseball team are also mentioned. Many of Schilder's cartoons called for the conservation of natural resources.
Of particular interest are Schilder’s cartoons drawn during World War II. Schilder’s depiction of the war and its effects went beyond the political as he often focused on home front activities and hardships including scrap metal drives, victory gardens and the rationing of food and other materials, while calling for "Patriotism before pleasure" as one title encouraged. Schilder also produced a handful of cartoons that cautioned against being overly optimistic in predictions for a quick victory. He frequently referred to Axis leaders by nicknames including Herr Hitler, Herr Ohito (Hirohito) and the Herrless One (Mussolini).
Schilder's original art is dated only with years (there are also some undated cartoons). Several dated pieces are mounted. Undated work has been arranged in alphabetical order by caption. Items vary in size but the majority are between approximately 11" x 14" and 14" x 16". The cartoons were drawn primarily in ink on illustration board. Some feature light crayon shading.
In addition to editorial and general interest cartoons, there are also 32 original drawings of World War II leaders. These portraits generally measure 8 1/4" x 11 1/4" and several are mounted. Also included are fourteen original Cinder comic strips featuring Schilder's signature black cat, Steve.
There are also 26 original drawings by other artists, many of which were presented as gifts to Schilder. See the inventory for a listing.
Biographical material (1909-1950) contains a few pieces of personal correspondence, articles on Schilder and his work, two photographs of Schilder and a small folder of miscellaneous items.
Printed material (1921-1945) offers examples of Schilder's work as it appeared in various non-newspaper formats particularly trade and industry publications, particulary from Traveler's Insurance. Several folders are related to Syracuse and the upstate New York region including material on the American Legion, Mohawk Carpet Mills, and various other businesses and organizations. Some local material is related to the Syracuse Post-Standard.
Schilder was an avid clipper of items from magazines and newspapers. Clippings (1912-1950) is generally comprised of two types of material: material clipped from newspapers and magazines (work not drawn by Schilder) and cartoons (particularly editorial cartoons). Included are Schilder’s editorial cartoons from the Syracuse Post-Standard as well as clippings of cartoons by other cartoonists (such as Carey Orr, Herb Roth, J.N. Ding Darling, H.T. Webster, Warren King, Gasoline Alley and the Gumps). Included is a Ding drawing done exclusively for the Syracuse Post-Standard. Schilder also clipped a plethora of illustrations, advertisements and imagery from publications, ranging from small scraps to full pages about animals, transportation, illustrations of people, and furniture. Many clippings contain spot color and are from New York newspapers. Also of interest in this series is a scrapbook containing clippings, photos and portraits of other cartoonists.
Proofs (1915-1944) includes several proofs of cartoons including editorial cartoons and The Moneybacks comic strip. However, the majority of the proofs are caricatures appearing to be of prominent businessmen. They may be from the work, Club Men of Indianapolis in Caricature or a similar publication. Many of these caricature portraits have the name of other artists.
Photographs contains 27 undated photographs kept by Schilder. They depict animals, children and sports (boxing, horse racing, Gene Tunney). Of particular interest is a photo of the Ku Klux Klan and a movie still from Flaming Frontier.
Arrangement of the Collection
Dated cartoons are arranged chronologically by year. Oversized mounted cartoons are arranged separately. Undated cartoons are arranged alphabetically by letter. Undated cartoons without titles are located at the end of the Schilder section of the original artwork series.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
One printed item pertaining to the Wizard of Oz (with no specific connection to Schilder) has been transferred to the
L. Frank Baum Papers.
The following have been sent to Rare Books.
Hart Schaffner & Marx Style Book (1926)
one issue of Indian News (Indian motorcycle company, 1931)
Zonite: a New and Remarkable Discovery product booklet (1922)
issues (15 items) of the Legionnaire publication from Syracuse Post 41 (1943-1945, 1947-1948)
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; New York State; Schilder, Edgar F.; Stalin, Joseph, 1879-1953 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Hirohito, Emperor of Japan, 1901-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Mussolini, Benito, 1883-1945 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Hitler, Adolf, 1889-1945 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Post-standard (Syracuse, N.Y.); American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Caricatures and cartoons -- New York (State) -- Syracuse.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Cartoonists -- New York (State) -- Syracuse.; Fishing -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Editorial cartoons -- New York (State) -- Syracuse.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; Rationing -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Taxation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Sports -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Inflation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Liberty bonds -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Vacations -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Victory gardens -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World War, 1939-1945 -- Social aspects -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1900-1945 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Nature conservation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Winter -- Caricatures and Cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1901-1953 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Onondaga County (N.Y.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Oneida Lake (N.Y.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoons (humorous images); Comic strips.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Editorial cartoons.; Photographs.; Posters.; Proofs (printed matter); Scrapbooks.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of James F. and Dorothea Wright (Schilder's son-in-law and daughter), 1968, 1970.
Inventory
- Original Artwork
  - Artwork by Schilder
    - Cartoons
      - 1918, 1925, 1932-1933, 18 items (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
      - 1934, 11 items (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
      - 1934, 8 items (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
      - 1935, 11 items (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
      - 1935, 11 items (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
      - 1936, 14 items (Oversize 1, Folder 6)
      - 1936, 12 items (Oversize 1, Folder 7)
      - 1937, 14 items (Oversize 1, Folder 8)
      - 1938, 18 items (Oversize 1, Folder 9)
      - 1939, 12 items (Oversize 1, Folder 10)
      - 1939, 12 items (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
      - 1939, 12 items (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
      - Circa 1930s, 2 items (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
      - 1940, 10 items (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
      - 1940, 11 items (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
      - 1940, 15 items (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
      - 1941, 12 items (Oversize 2, Folder 7)
      - 1942, 14 items (Oversize 2, Folder 8)
      - 1942, 25 items (Oversize 2, Folder 9)
      - 1942, 18 items (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
      - 1942, 19 items (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
      - 1943, 16 items (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
      - 1943, 17 items (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
      - 1943, 17 items (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
      - 1943, 17 items (Oversize 4, Folder 1)
      - 1943, 17 items (Oversize 4, Folder 2)
      - 1943, 20 items (Oversize 4, Folder 3)
      - 1944, 16 items (Oversize 4, Folder 4)
      - 1944, 17 items (Oversize 4, Folder 5)
      - 1944, 17 items (Oversize 4, Folder 6)
      - 1944, 17 items (Oversize 4, Folder 7)
      - 1944, 16 items (Oversize 5, Folder 1)
      - 1944, 17 items (Oversize 5, Folder 2)
      - 1944, 20 items (Oversize 5, Folder 3)
      - 1945, 19 items (Oversize 5, Folder 4)
      - 1945, 15 items (Oversize 5, Folder 5)
      - 1945, 16 items (Oversize 5, Folder 6)
      - 1945, 16 items (Oversize 5, Folder 7)
      - 1945, 16 items (Oversize 5, Folder 8)
      - 1945, 16 items (Oversize 6, Folder 1)
      - 1946, 18 items (Oversize 6, Folder 2)
      - 1946, 18 items (Oversize 6, Folder 3)
      - 1946, 17 items (Oversize 6, Folder 4)
      - 1947, 18 items (Oversize 6, Folder 5)
      - 1947, 17 items (Oversize 6, Folder 6)
      - 1947, 16 items (Oversize 6, Folder 7)
      - 1948, 15 items (Oversize 7, Folder 1)
      - 1948, 15 items (Oversize 7, Folder 2)
      - 1948, 15 items (Oversize 7, Folder 3)
      - 1948, 7 items (Oversize 7, Folder 4)
      - 1949, 15 items (Oversize 7, Folder 5)
      - 1949, 18 items (Oversize 7, Folder 6)
      - 1949, 17 items (Oversize 7, Folder 7)
      - Circa 1940s, 14 items (Oversize 7, Folder 8)
      - Circa 1940s, 13 items (Oversize 7, Folder 9)
      - Circa 1940s, 12 items (Oversize 7, Folder 10)
      - 1950, 20 items (Oversize 7, Folder 11)
      - Oversized mounted 1934, 1936-1938, 7 items (Oversize 8, Folder 1)
      - Oversized mounted 1939-1941, 8 items (Oversize 8, Folder 2)
      - Oversized mounted 1942, 10 items (Oversize 8, Folder 3)
      - Oversized mounted 1942, 9 items (Oversize 9, Folder 1)
      - Oversized mounted 1942, 9 items (Oversize 9, Folder 2)
      - Undated A-B, 18 items (Oversize 10, Folder 1)
      - Undated C-F, 12 items (Oversize 10, Folder 2)
      - Undated G-H, 15 items (Oversize 10, Folder 3)
      - Undated I-L, 17 items (Oversize 10, Folder 4)
      - Undated M, 16 items (Oversize 10, Folder 5)
      - Undated N-O, 9 items (Oversize 10, Folder 6)
      - Undated P-R, 10 items (Oversize 10, Folder 7)
      - Undated S, 12 items (Oversize 10, Folder 8)
      - Undated T, 14 items (Oversize 10, Folder 9)
      - Undated U-W, 17 items (Oversize 10, Folder 10)
      - Undated Untitled, 17 items (Oversize 11, Folder 1)
      - Undated Untitled, 14 items (Oversize 11, Folder 2)
      - Undated Untitled, 14 items (Oversize 11, Folder 3)
      - Undated Untitled, 13 items (Oversize 11, Folder 4)
      - Undated Untitled, 14 items (Oversize 11, Folder 5)
      - Undated Untitled, 9 items (Oversize 11, Folder 6)
    - Sketches
      - Pencil sketches, undated; 6 items (Oversize 13)
    - Comic strips
      - Cinder, 1922; 4 panel strip featuring Steve the cat; 7 ½" x 21 ½" 14 items (Oversize 13)
    - World War II portraits of leaders and politicians, 1940-1943; undated; 32 items (Oversize 12)
  - Artwork by others, 26 items (Oversize 13)
    - Original drawings by other artists, undated except where noted (Oversize 13)
      Ray Barnes- (1936)
      J.F. Bronstrup- [Pancho Villa]
      Dietz -"Schilderian Demise" (1944)
      Rudolph Dirks- [To the Contest Editor]
      Clifton Flood- "Untitled", [Summer school prof. Kline's class] (2 items, 1938, 1940)
      H.E. Godwin- [This is the Life (man fishing)]
      Holloway [caricature portrait of Schilder]
      C.R. Macauley- "Will It Hatch?"
      Gus Mager - [cartoon contest]
      Elmer R. Messner- "No Room for Other Shadows" (1940)
      W.K. Patrick- "Disqualified", "Whoo-pee!", [Brigandage] (3 items)
      Harold Tucker Webster- "Life's Darkest Moment" (Jan. 9, 1923)
      Gluyas Williams- "A Strain on the Family" (1926- inscribed to H.P. Bull)
      Eugene Zimmerman- "Foolish Remarks", "On George Washington", "Chicken Talk", "Business Awakening", "Well That's Encouraging", "Take Notice" (8 items, circa 1918, 1932)
      Unknown artist- "Mother's Day"
    - Original artwork- J.N. "Ding" Darling- "Defying the Laws of Gravitation", undated (Map-case 1, Drawer 100)
- Clippings
  - Cartoonists' obituaries, 1935; undated; Frank Ladendorf, Eugene Zimmerman (Box 1)
  - Cartoons by others (2 folders), circa 1912-1942; undated (Box 1)
  - Editorial Cartoons, 1919-1922; 1925,; 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - Editorial Cartoons (6 folders), 1930-1939; circa 1930s (Box 1)
  - Editorial Cartoons (7 folders), 1940-1945 (Box 2)
  - Editorial Cartoons (5 folders), 1946-1950; undated (Box 3)
  - Lion's Club newspaper - East Syracuse, NY, 23 Dec 1949 (Box 3)
  - Magazine clippings (3 folders), circa 1910-1924 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper articles, 1935; 1938-1939,; undated; several related to Ten Eyck (Box 3)
  - Newspaper clippings (3 folders), circa 1910-1924 (Box 3)
  - "Taxes After the War" article, undated (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, undated; contains clippings, copies of Schilder's artwork, clippings of portraits of other cartoonists, family photos (Oversize 11)
- Biographical material
  - Correspondence, 1909; 1943-1944,; 1950,; undated (Box 4)
  - Newspaper articles about Schilder, 1932; 1939,; 1940,; 1943,; undated (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Photographs of Schilder, undated; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Syracuse Art Museum Quarterly Bulletin, 1943; 2 items (Box 4)
- Proofs
  - Cartoon proofs, 1919-1921; 1938,; 1940,; 1942-1944,; undated (Box 4)
  - International Syndicate- Schilder's Cartoons, 1915 Dec; 1916 Mar; Schilder's 6 weekly cartoons (Box 4)
  - The Moneybacks, undated; represents 12 days of the comic strip (Box 4)
  - Portraits (4 folders), undated; possibly from Club men of Indianapolis in caricature (Box 4)
- Printed Material
  - American Humane Association posters- Albany, NY, 1945; 4 items (Oversize 13)
  - Better Health - Syracuse, NY, circa 1927; undated (Box 4)
  - Cartoons by others, 1932; undated; 2 items; Burt Thomas and Eugene Zimmerman (Box 4)
  - Christmas greetings, 1932-1937; 1941,; undated (Box 4)
  - Columbian Crew clippings, undated (Box 4)
  - Indian Motorcycle Company - Indian News, 1930-1932; One complete issue has been transferred to Rare Books. (Box 4)
  - Insurance Pictorial, 1930-1931; 3 issues (Box 4)
  - Legionnaire Syracuse Post 41, 1943-1945; 15 complete issues have been transferred to Rare Books.; covers only (Box 5)
  - "Life and Adventures of a Mohawk Merchandiser" - Mohawk Carpet Mills, 1928-1930; undated; 30 items (Box 5)
  - National War Fund Cartoon Service, Aug 1944 (Box 5)
  - A Page for the Children, undated; 14 items (Box 5)
  - Sears Roebuck and Company (Utica, Syracuse, Auburn, New York) comic strip, 1931; in color (Box 5)
  - Syracuse, New York and New York (State), 1921; 1926,; 1929; 1931,; 1935; includes material related to the Syracuse Post-Standard (Box 5)
  - Syracuse Washing Machine Corporation Efficiency Contest Bulletin of Divisional Standings, 1927-1928; undated (Box 5)
  - Traveler's Insurance, 1924-1930; 1932-1933,; 1942,; undated; brochures, advertisements, Protection magazine (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous clippings of Schilder's artwork, 1921-1922; 1924,; 1926-1930,; 1935-1936,; undated (Box 5)
  - Writings by Schilder, circa 1925; undated (Box 5)
- Photographs
  - International Newsreel and Syracuse Post Standard photographs, undated; 27 items; parts cut from larger photographs (Box 4)
    Subject matter includes: animals, children, sports (boxing, horse racing, Gene Tunney), Flaming Frontier movie still, Ku Klux Klan
Index to cartoons
The following is a list of predominant people, places and subjects appearing in the editorial cartoons in this collection. The list is not exhaustive. Some subjects may require you to browse with alternative terms.
B= Box, F= Folder. For example: B1F1= Box 1 Folder 1.
Africa B3F2 B7F10 B10F4
Albania B7F10
Argentina B5F1-B5F2 B5F6
armed forces B3F1-B3F2 B3F4 B4F2 B4F4 B5F1 B5F6 B5F8 B7F9
Asia B3F3
astronomy B2F2
Australia B10F1
automobile accidents B2F7 B6F4 B8F1
automobile industry B4F1 B5F4
Axis powers B2F5-B2F6 B2F8-B2F9 B3F4 B4F1 B5F1 B7F10 B9F1-B9F2
Barkley, Alben W. B4F4
bills B1F1 B2F2 B3F1 B7F3 B7F5 B8F2 B10F9
birth rate B8F3
black market B3F4 B4F2 B5F2 B5F6 B6F2 B7F8
Boy Scouts B7F11
Britain B2F6 B5F2 B6F3 B7F8 B10F9
Browder, Earl B5F2
business B7F6-B7F7 B8F1
canning B1F8
capitalism B7F7 B10F8
Cardiff Giant B6F5
Central New York B1F1-B1F2 B1F4 B1F6-B1F7 B1F9 B2F5-B2F6 B4F1 B4F3 B5F1 B5F4-B5F5 B5F8 B6F2 B6F5 B7F3 B7F7 B7F11 B10F5 B10F9 B11F3
charity B6F4 B6F7 B7F2 B8F1 B10F1
Charles, Prince of Wales B7F5
China B2F3 B3F3 B7F5 B10F9
Churchill, Winston B3F3 B8F3
circus B7F11
civil rights B10F2
coal industry B6F7 B7F6 B7F11 B10F4 B10F6
Cold War B10F6
Colgate University B1F1 B2F6 B5F3 B6F4 B10F1-B10F2 B10F5 B11F2
collectivism B7F5
communism B5F2 B6F3-B6F6 B7F2-B7F3 B10F1-B10F2 B10F8
concentration camps B10F4 B11F3
Congress B4F4-B4F5 B6F5-B6F6 B7F3-B7F4
conservation, in New York State B5F3 B6F2 B6F4 B7F2
consumers B1F4 B6F5
Cornell University B1F1-B1F2 B1F9 B2F1 B8F2
cost of living B5F7 B10F3
crime B7F3
daylight savings time B2F2 B2F9 B3F2 B5F7 B6F4 B7F3 B7F6 B10F1-B10F2 B10F5 B10F9-B10F10
democracy B2F4-B2F5 B6F3 B6F5-B6F6
Democratic Party B4F5 B4F7 B6F1 B7F1-B7F3
Dewey, Thomas B6F3-B6F4 B7F7
disarmament B6F7
diseases B2F4 B6F6 B7F6
Dobie, Gil B1F5
draft B2F5
driving B4F3
economy B4F7 B5F7 B6F2
education B2F6 B10F8
elections B7F2-B7F3 B7F5
Fair Deal B7F5-B7F6
Farley, Jim B2F8
farming B1F2 B2F6 B4F1 B4F4 B5F3 B6F5 B7F1 B7F3 B7F5 B10F8
Fascism B2F9
fashion B1F1 B1F3 B1F5 B2F4 B5F4-B5F5 B7F5 B10F9 B11F4
Finland B5F2 B8F1
fishing B1F1-B1F6 B1F9-B2F1 B2F5 B2F9 B3F3 B3F5-B4F1 B4F7-B5F1 B5F4-B5F5 B6F1-B6F4 B7F4 B7F6 B7F9 B7F11 B9F1-B9F2 B10F1-B10F4 B10F7-B10F8 B11F4
Florida B2F7
foreign policy B4F5 B5F1 B5F7
France B4F5 B5F1-B5F2
free speech B10F4
gardening B1F7-B1F8 B1F10-B2F1 B6F3-B6F5 B7F3-B7F4 B7F6-B7F8 B7F10 B10F3 B10F5 B10F9-B11F1 B11F5
gas prices B2F6 B3F1 B7F7
Germany B3F3 B4F2 B5F2 B5F7-B6F1 B7F1 B7F5 B8F3 B10F1 B10F4-B10F5 B10F7 B11F6
Goebbels, Joseph B4F5 B4F7 B6F1
Great Depression B1F1
Greece B2F4
Hirohito B2F5 B2F9-B3F2 B3F4-B4F2 B4F4-B4F5 B5F7 B6F1 B7F9 B8F3 B9F1-B10F1
Hitler, Adolf B2F5 B2F8-B4F2 B4F4-B4F5 B4F7-B5F3 B5F6-B5F7 B6F1 B7F8-B7F9 B8F1 B8F3-B10F2 B10F4 B10F9
holidays B1F1 B1F3-B1F4 B1F8 B2F1 B2F5-B2F8 B3F2 B5F6 B5F8 B6F6-B7F1 B7F3-B7F5 B7F7 B8F1 B8F3 B10F1 B10F3 B10F9-B10F10 B11F3-B11F5
Hoover, Hebert B2F9
housing B6F2 B6F7
industry (general) B1F1 B4F7 B6F3 B8F3
inflation B2F7-B2F8 B3F1 B3F4 B4F7 B5F8 B6F3-B6F4 B6F6-B7F2 B7F4 B7F7-B7F8 B7F10 B10F10
insurance B1F10
Italy B4F1-B4F2 B4F5 B5F1-B5F2 B5F8 B7F3 B7F10 B9F1
Japan B2F8-B3F2 B4F2 B4F5 B4F7 B5F7 B6F1 B7F8 B8F3-B9F2
Kerr, Andy B1F5
Korea B10F2
lease lend operations B2F6-B2F7
Lewis, John L. B6F3 B6F6 B7F2 B7F6 B7F11 B10F6
Lincoln, Abraham B7F11
Lynch, James M. B1F1
MacArthur, Douglas B5F1 B8F3
Mussolini, Benito B2F9-B3F3 B3F5-B4F2 B4F5 B5F6 B7F8 B7F10 B9F1-B9F2
national debt B5F6 B6F3 B6F7 B7F6 B7F9
Nazism B2F9 B3F5 B4F4 B4F7-B5F2 B6F3 B8F3 B10F4-B10F5
New Deal B1F6-B1F7 B1F9 B2F3-B2F5 B2F8 B3F3 B4F7-B5F1 B7F9
New York (State) B6F1 B6F5 B7F2 B7F7 B10F2
North Atlantic Security Pact B7F7 B10F3
nuclear weapons B5F5 B5F7 B6F2-B6F3 B10F4 B10F8
oil B2F8
Oneida Lake B1F1 B1F4 B1F6 B1F9-B2F1 B2F6 B2F9 B3F2 B5F6-B5F8 B7F8-B7F9 B8F1 B10F3-B10F4 B10F6
Onondaga County B3F4 B4F3 B5F6 B5F8 B6F7 B7F6 B7F8 B8F1 B10F9
Onondaga Lake B2F1 B10F6 B10F9
Owens, Jesse B1F8
Palestine B7F1
peace B5F2 B5F7 B6F1 B6F3 B6F6 B10F1-B10F2 B10F8
Pennsylvania State University B1F4 B1F6 B1F9-B1F10
Philippines B5F1
Poland B4F5
politics B2F3 B4F4 B5F2
pollution B5F6 B10F6
Prohibition B1F1 B1F3 B10F2 B10F9
Prussia B4F5
Pyle, Ernie B5F6
racism B5F7
rationing B2F8-B4F1 B4F3 B4F5 B5F1-B5F3 B5F5-B6F4 B7F8-B7F10 B8F3-B9F2 B10F2 B10F4 B10F9-B10F10 B11F6
Red Cross B3F1 B3F5 B6F1 B7F4 B7F8
religion B7F6
Republican Party B4F4-B4F5 B4F7 B6F1 B7F2 B7F11 B10F2
Rommel, Erwin B3F4-B3F5
Roosevelt, Franklin D. B2F4-B2F5 B3F3 B4F4 B5F2 B7F8-B7F10 B8F1 B8F3 B10F6 B11F3
Russia B2F8 B3F1-B3F3 B3F5 B4F2 B4F5 B5F1-B5F2 B5F6 B6F1 B6F3 B7F2 B7F5 B7F8-B7F9 B9F2-B10F1 B10F4 B10F8-B10F9
San Francisco B5F7 B10F5
savings bonds B10F1 B10F4
scrap metal drives B2F8 B5F2 B7F10 B9F2
social security B10F8
socialism B2F5
South America B5F1
Soviet Union B4F4
space exploration B6F2
sports B1F1-B1F7 B1F9-B2F2 B2F7 B2F9 B3F2 B4F3-B4F4 B5F3 B5F8 B6F4-B7F1 B7F3 B7F5-B7F7 B7F9 B7F11-B8F1 B10F2-B10F5 B10F7-B10F9 B11F1-B11F5
Stalin, Joseph B2F3 B3F2-B3F3 B4F2 B4F4 B6F7-B7F1 B7F5-B7F7 B8F1 B8F3 B10F2-B10F4 B10F8 B10F10
state fair B1F9 B2F6 B10F4
steel industry B6F2 B10F4
strikes B1F7 B4F1 B5F7 B6F2 B7F2 B7F6 B7F10-B7F11 B10F4 B10F6